<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Security on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/tags/security/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Security on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2023 huizhou92</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 15:07:08 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://huizhou92.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Top 9 VPN Alternative Technologies For Future Remote Access</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/top-9-vpn-alternative-technologies-for-future-remote-access/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 15:07:08 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/top-9-vpn-alternative-technologies-for-future-remote-access/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:1400/1*UNopDeZUWU-b3bzZWVpW2A.png" alt="Featured image of post Top 9 VPN Alternative Technologies For Future Remote Access" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a long time, VPNs have been the preferred technology for secure remote access. However, with the popularization and normalization of remote/hybrid work, traditional VPNs have proven inadequate in dealing with complex network environments and new security threats, exposing many fatal flaws.&lt;br&gt;
This article will introduce the nine hottest VPN alternative technologies in the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Do We Need to Replace VPN?&lt;/strong&gt; The application of VPN in large-scale remote work has shown various limitations, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expanded Attack Surface&lt;/strong&gt;: VPN connections extend the insecure network where users are located to the enterprise network, increasing the possibility of attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited Encryption Capability&lt;/strong&gt;: VPNs usually only encrypt transmission traffic and lack comprehensive security stack support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weak User Authentication&lt;/strong&gt;: Many VPNs do not enforce multi-factor authentication (MFA), making them easy to invade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequent Vulnerabilities&lt;/strong&gt;: For example, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvekey.cgi?keyword=SonicWall&amp;#43;SSLVPN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SonicWall SSLVPN&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvekey.cgi?keyword=&amp;#43;Pulse&amp;#43;Secure&amp;#43;VPN&amp;#43;&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pulse Secure VPN&lt;/a&gt; have been found to have serious vulnerabilities many times and have become targets of attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- more--&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The famous&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Colonial Pipeline Ransomware Attack&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;precisely took advantage of the leaked usernames and passwords of VPN devices, resulting in the complete control of the network.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risks and shortcomings of traditional VPNs are already obvious. Enterprises must make strategic investments in VPN alternative technology solutions and evaluate some key factors when considering alternative remote access solutions. The most important thing is to include the zero-trust principle: &lt;strong&gt;requiring strong authentication for each connection attempt, evaluating compliance, implementing the principle of least privilege, and establishing a trusted connection whenever an attempt is made to access company data or services&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key focus point when choosing a VPN alternative technology solution is to support modern management. Centralized management is the first step, and automated functions (such as patch management, policies (authentication, encryption, risk scoring, etc.), and integration with other components of the security stack) can mitigate modern risks and attack vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a detailed analysis of nine VPN alternative technologies. It not only lists their core functions but also explores practical application scenarios and key considerations in implementation, providing enterprises with richer security solutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zero-trust-network-access-ztna&#34;&gt;Zero Trust Network Access (ZTNA)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zero Trust Network Access (ZTNA) is essentially proxy access to applications and data on the network. Before access is granted, users and devices will be challenged and verified. The zero-trust approach can perform the essential functions of a VPN, such as granting access to certain systems and networks, but adds an extra layer of security through least-privilege access, authentication, employment verification, and credential storage. Therefore, if an attacker successfully infects a system, the damage is limited to what that system can access. The zero-trust model can also include network monitoring solutions to detect suspicious behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Functions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Authentication: Conduct multi-factor authentication (MFA) for users and devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Principle of Least Privilege: Limit user access and only grant the minimum privileges required to complete tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic Access Control: Analyze risks in real-time and adjust access privileges according to the risk level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed Teams: Help multinational companies protect the access of distributed employees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensitive Data Environments include access control of customer data in financial institutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrating with existing identity management systems (such as Active Directory) is necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure detailed access policies to reduce the impact of false positives on the user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representative Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.zscaler.com/resources/security-terms-glossary/what-is-zero-trust-network-access&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zscaler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.okta.com/zero-trust/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Okta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/cyberpedia/what-is-zero-trust-network-access-ztna&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Palo Alto Networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;secure-access-service-edge-sase&#34;&gt;Secure Access Service Edge (SASE)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Zero Trust Network Access (ZTNA) model, each user and device will be verified and inspected before being allowed access, both at the network and application levels. However, zero trust is only part of the solution; all traffic from one endpoint to another cannot be monitored. SASE provides simplified management and operation, reduced costs, and improved visibility and security through an additional layer of network functions and an underlying cloud-native security architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Functions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of Network and Security Functions, Including SD-WAN, cloud-native firewalls (FWaaS), and DNS protection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud-Native Architecture: Improve network performance and reduce hardware deployment costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global Coverage: Achieve secure access for global users through distributed data centers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global Business Expansion: Help enterprises quickly deploy secure remote connections in multiple countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Learning Platforms: Protect the data privacy of students and teaching staff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure the interoperability of different components, such as the seamless integration of ZTNA, SWG, and CASB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select SASE suppliers with high availability to ensure the continuity of critical business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representative Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cisco.com/site/us/en/solutions/secure-access-service-edge-sase/index.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.netskope.com/products/secure-access-service-edge&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Netskope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.fortinet.com/products/sase&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Fortinet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-defined-perimeter-sdp&#34;&gt;Software Defined Perimeter (SDP)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software Defined Perimeter (SDP) is usually implemented within a broader zero-trust strategy. It is a network perimeter based on software rather than hardware and is an effective alternative to traditional VPN solutions. It allows MFA to divide the network and supports rules that restrict access by specific users. Once suspicious behavior is detected, SDP can more easily block access to resources, isolate potential threats, minimize the damage caused by attacks, and maintain productivity in the case of false positives instead of completely disabling devices and making users unable to do meaningful work. The software-defined aspect of SDP also enables automation, allowing other tools in the network to interact with SDP and mitigate these risks in real-time when dangerous behavior is identified. In the era of intelligent and automated cyberattacks, the automation capabilities of SDP are critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Functions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logical Isolation: Access control is based on identity rather than network location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic Threat Isolation: Automatically block access after detecting abnormal activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High Degree of Automation: Real-time adjustment and response through machine learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic Workplaces: Support employees working in different locations while ensuring security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partner Access Control: Limit the network access rights of external partners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate with existing network tools, such as SIEM (Security Information and Event Management).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design flexible rules to balance security and business efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representative Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.perimeter81.com/software-defined-perimeter&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Perimeter 81&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.appgate.com/support/software-defined-perimeter-support/client&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Appgate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/access-management/software-defined-perimeter/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-defined-wide-area-network-sd-wan&#34;&gt;Software Defined Wide Area Network (SD-WAN)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;VPNs rely on a router-centered model to distribute control functions in the network, where routers route traffic according to IP addresses and access control lists (ACL). However, the Software Defined Wide Area Network (SD-WAN) relies on software and centralized control functions. It can handle traffic according to the organization’s needs based on priority, security, and quality of service requirements, thus guiding the traffic in the WAN. SD-WAN is particularly important because edge computing accounts for an increasingly high proportion of enterprise networks. SD-WAN can dynamically manage these scattered connections without using hundreds or thousands of sensors (many of which are deployed in less secure locations) that require VPN connections or firewall rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Functions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic Traffic Management: Optimize traffic routing based on application priority and network conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built-in Security: Support encryption, authentication, and real-time threat detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centralized Management: Manage multiple branch office networks through a single interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT): Manage and protect large-scale IoT device networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-branch Enterprises include retail chains or warehousing and logistics across regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider real-time sensitive applications&amp;rsquo; quality of service (QoS) requirements (such as video conferencing).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regularly update software and configurations to respond to emerging threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representative Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/products/software-defined-edge/velocloud-sd-wan&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hpe.com/us/en/solutions/silver-peak.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Silver Peak (HPE)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.aryaka.com/sd-wan/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aryaka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;identity-and-access-management-iam-and-privileged-access-management-pam&#34;&gt;Identity and Access Management (IAM) and Privileged Access Management (PAM)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared with traditional VPNs that usually only require passwords, solutions that adopt a comprehensive verification process to confirm the validity of login attempts provide higher protection. With Identity and Access Management (IAM), network administrators can ensure that each user has authorized access rights and can track each network session. IAM is an alternative to VPN and a viable solution for protecting applications and services. It is the foundation of many other solutions in this article. Simplified identity and authentication policy management enhances every system that uses it for authentication and utilizes risk-based authentication and MFA to enhance security when appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Functions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAM: Centralize the management of user authentication and authorization, support risk assessment, and single sign-on (SSO).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PAM: Protect high-privilege accounts and support regular password rotation and activity monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-Sensitivity Operations: Protect IT administrators and key system accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industries with Strict Compliance Requirements, Such as HIPAA compliance in the medical industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure dynamic access risk assessment combined with artificial intelligence (AI).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regularly train users to reduce the possibility of credential abuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representative Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.okta.com/iam-identity-and-access-management/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Okta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cyberark.com/what-is/iam/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CyberArk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.onelogin.com/learn/iam&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OneLogin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;unified-endpoint-management-tools-uem&#34;&gt;Unified Endpoint Management Tools (UEM)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andrew Hewitt, a senior analyst at Forrester, said that conditional access through Unified Endpoint Management (UEM) tools can provide a VPN-free experience; the agent running on the device will evaluate various conditions before allowing someone to access specific resources. “For example, the solution can evaluate device compliance, identity information, and user behavior to determine whether the person can access enterprise data. Usually, UEM providers will integrate with ZTNA providers to increase protection.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Functions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conditional Access: Before granting access, check the device status (patches, encryption, configuration).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-Time Monitoring: Support remote locking, data erasure, and threat detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comprehensive Compatibility: Cover multiple devices such as desktops, laptops, smartphones, and tablets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile Office: Applicable to employees using personal devices to access enterprise resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-Frequency Device Updates include the POS systems in retail stores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure compatibility with other security tools such as ZTNA or SASE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarify user privacy policies to avoid disputes caused by device management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representative Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-Workspace-ONE-UEM/index.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;VMware Workspace ONE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/business/microsoft-intune&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Microsoft Intune&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ivanti.com/unified-endpoint-management&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ivanti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-desktop-infrastructure-vdi-or-desktop-as-a-service-daas&#34;&gt;Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) or Desktop as a Service (DaaS)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hewitt pointed out that the Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) or Desktop as a Service solution “essentially transmits computing from the cloud (or local server), so there will be no local data on the device.” He added that sometimes organizations will use it as an alternative to VPN but still need to conduct checks at the device level and user authentication to protect access. “However, the advantage of this is that, unlike traditional VPNs, VDI does not copy any data from the virtual session to the local client.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Functions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Isolation: All operations are carried out in a virtual environment, and data is not stored locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centralized Control: Simplify patch management and the implementation of security policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible Expansion: Quickly add or remove users according to requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensitive Industries: Protect customer data in the legal, insurance, and medical fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disaster Recovery Environments: Quickly recover critical business during a disaster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invest in a high-performance virtualization platform to ensure the user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure additional access controls to avoid damage by malicious users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representative Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.citrix.com/en-us/citrix-daas/overview.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Citrix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.vmware.com/en/VMware-Horizon-DaaS/index.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;VMware Horizon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/desktop-and-application-streaming/tag/daas/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Amazon WorkSpaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;secure-web-gateway-swg&#34;&gt;Secure Web Gateway (SWG)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Secure Web Gateway (SWG) can protect Web applications hosted in local or private clouds. Although SWG is a component of the SASE architecture, it can also be implemented independently of the overall SASE strategy to implement policies around authentication, URL filtering, and data loss prevention. It can even prevent malware from passing through connections. SWG is usually directly connected to line-of-business applications. Software agents can also be installed in the local network to connect to applications or services. This flexibility makes SWG a simple choice for improving the security situation of enterprises without major changes to the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Functions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URL Filtering: Block access to malicious websites based on policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Loss Prevention (DLP): Prevent sensitive information from being leaked through Web channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threat Protection: Detect and block malware transmitted through the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remote Access: Protect employees’ access to enterprise applications through public Wi-Fi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Application Security: Protect services deployed by enterprises in private or public clouds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate with the organization’s SIEM and SOAR systems to enhance incident response capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure compliance with industry compliance requirements (such as GDPR).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representative Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.zscaler.com/resources/security-terms-glossary/what-is-secure-web-gateway&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zscaler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.broadcom.com/products/cybersecurity/network/web-protection&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Symantec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.forcepoint.com/cyber-edu/what-is-secure-web-gateway&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Forcepoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud-access-security-broker-casb&#34;&gt;Cloud Access Security Broker (CASB)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cloud Access Security Broker (CASB) is a component of SASE and can be independently deployed to supplement or replace the needs of a VPN. CASB can implement security policies (authentication requirements, encryption configurations, malware detection, managed/non-managed device access, etc.) between end users and SaaS applications. Although this use case does not meet the definition of a VPN alternative (requiring access to local company resources), it replaces some enterprise controls that traditionally could only be achieved by guiding users through a central control point. It is a typical VPN use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Functions&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unified Policy Management: Monitor the interaction between users and cloud services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Visibility: Distinguish between managed and unmanaged devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-Time Threat Detection: Identify suspicious behavior and block malicious operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application Scenarios&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-Cloud Management: Ensure consistent security policies in a multi-cloud environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SaaS Application Security: Includes enterprise-level applications like Salesforce and Office 365.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementation Key Points&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure detailed policies to cover multiple devices and access scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuously monitor user activities and optimize access rights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Representative Manufacturers&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.netskope.com/products/casb&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Netskope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.atlassian.com/software/guard/mcafee&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;McAfee MVISION Cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/security/business/security-101/what-is-a-cloud-access-security-broker-casb&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Microsoft Defender for Cloud Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>11 Tips for Detecting and Responding to Intrusions on Linux</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/11-tips-for-detecting-and-responding-to-intrusions-on-linux/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 09:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/11-tips-for-detecting-and-responding-to-intrusions-on-linux/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/8a6d3ceaf014801bc93c355d1e164d4e.png" alt="Featured image of post 11 Tips for Detecting and Responding to Intrusions on Linux" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the increasing popularity of open-source products, it is crucial for a backend engineer to be able to clearly identify whether an abnormal machine has been compromised. Based on my personal work experience, I have compiled several common scenarios of machines being hacked for reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is first published in the medium MPP plan. If you are a medium user, please follow me in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.huizhou92.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
     
    .notice {
        --title-color: #fff;
        --title-background-color: #6be;
        --content-color: #444;
        --content-background-color: #e7f2fa;
    }

    .notice.info {
        --title-background-color: #fb7;
        --content-background-color: #fec;
    }

    .notice.tip {
        --title-background-color: #5a5;
        --content-background-color: #efe;
    }

    .notice.warning {
        --title-background-color: #c33;
        --content-background-color: #fee;
    }

     
    @media (prefers-color-scheme:dark) {
        .notice {
            --title-color: #fff;
            --title-background-color: #069;
            --content-color: #ddd;
            --content-background-color: #023;
        }

        .notice.info {
            --title-background-color: #a50;
            --content-background-color: #420;
        }

        .notice.tip {
            --title-background-color: #363;
            --content-background-color: #121;
        }

        .notice.warning {
            --title-background-color: #800;
            --content-background-color: #400;
        }
    }

    body.dark .notice {
        --title-color: #fff;
        --title-background-color: #069;
        --content-color: #ddd;
        --content-background-color: #023;
    }

    body.dark .notice.info {
        --title-background-color: #a50;
        --content-background-color: #420;
    }

    body.dark .notice.tip {
        --title-background-color: #363;
        --content-background-color: #121;
    }

    body.dark .notice.warning {
        --title-background-color: #800;
        --content-background-color: #400;
    }

     
    .notice {
        padding: 18px;
        line-height: 24px;
        margin-bottom: 24px;
        border-radius: 4px;
        color: var(--content-color);
        background: var(--content-background-color);
    }

    .notice p:last-child {
        margin-bottom: 0
    }

     
    .notice-title {
        margin: -18px -18px 12px;
        padding: 4px 18px;
        border-radius: 4px 4px 0 0;
        font-weight: 700;
        color: var(--title-color);
        background: var(--title-background-color);
    }

     
    .icon-notice {
        display: inline-flex;
        align-self: center;
        margin-right: 8px;
    }

    .icon-notice img,
    .icon-notice svg {
        height: 1em;
        width: 1em;
        fill: currentColor;
    }

    .icon-notice img,
    .icon-notice.baseline svg {
        top: .125em;
        position: relative;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice tips&#34; &gt;
    &lt;p class=&#34;notice-title&#34;&gt;
        &lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;
            
        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following scenarios are observed on CentOS systems and are similar for other Linux distributions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-intruders-may-delete-machine-logs&#34;&gt;1. Intruders May Delete Machine Logs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check if log information still exists or has been cleared using the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/42e92e989d964542c270e2815bde6619.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Image&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-intruders-may-create-a-new-file-for-storing-usernames-and-passwords&#34;&gt;2. Intruders May Create a New File for Storing Usernames and Passwords
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;code&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/etc/shadow&lt;/code&gt; files for any alterations using the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/e239d400fade65005ac316954e70fac8.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085544&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-intruders-may-modify-usernames-and-passwords&#34;&gt;3. Intruders May Modify Usernames and Passwords
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examine the contents of &lt;code&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/etc/shadow&lt;/code&gt; files for any changes using the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/b757b1e52c23abf2d352d480cbdfe85d.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085559&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-check-recent-successful-and-last-unsuccessful-login-events-on-the-machine&#34;&gt;4. Check Recent Successful and Last Unsuccessful Login Events on the Machine
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the log &amp;ldquo;/var/log/lastlog&amp;rdquo; using the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/ed0004d926cf0e1d7289d2437c25be21.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085611&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-use-who-to-view-all-currently-logged-in-users-on-the-machine&#34;&gt;5. Use &lt;code&gt;who&lt;/code&gt; to View All Currently Logged-in Users on the Machine
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the log file &amp;ldquo;/var/run/utmp&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/f9f029a7bdbba6d3b2ed542885c9dd75.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085623&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-use-last-to-view-users-logged-in-since-machine-creation&#34;&gt;6. Use &lt;code&gt;last&lt;/code&gt; to View Users Logged in Since Machine Creation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the log file &amp;ldquo;/var/log/wtmp&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/e1173e24b413d89a811a138ea74dcef2.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085717&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-use-ac-to-view-connection-time-in-hours-for-all-users-on-the-machine&#34;&gt;7. Use &lt;code&gt;ac&lt;/code&gt; to View Connection Time (in Hours) for All Users on the Machine
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the log file &amp;ldquo;/var/log/wtmp&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/1c311e4b87e54606127029433b6ecb6f.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085812&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-if-abnormal-traffic-is-detected&#34;&gt;8. If Abnormal Traffic is Detected
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use &amp;ldquo;tcpdump&amp;rdquo; to capture network packets or &amp;ldquo;iperf&amp;rdquo; to check traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;9-review-the-varlogsecure-log-file&#34;&gt;9. Review the &lt;code&gt;/var/log/secure&lt;/code&gt; Log File
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attempt to identify information about intruders using the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/6dd9205f9ffcab13df215be22965c6dd.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085837&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-identify-scripts-executed-by-abnormal-processes&#34;&gt;10. Identify Scripts Executed by Abnormal Processes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;a. Use the &lt;code&gt;top&lt;/code&gt; command to view the PID of abnormal processes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/38f534f788f32154517ab65359f3e9c9.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085848&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Search for the executable file of the process in the virtual file system directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/afb05ea6f7a54b5f129b365623fbccba.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085857&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;11-file-recovery-after-confirming-intrusion-and-deletion-of-important-files&#34;&gt;11. File Recovery After Confirming Intrusion and Deletion of Important Files
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a process opens a file, even if it&amp;rsquo;s deleted, it remains on the disk as long as the process keeps it open. To recover such files, use &lt;code&gt;lsof&lt;/code&gt; from the &lt;code&gt;/proc&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most &lt;code&gt;lsof&lt;/code&gt; information is stored in directories named after the process&amp;rsquo;s PID, such as &lt;code&gt;/proc/1234&lt;/code&gt;, containing information for PID 1234. Each process directory contains various files providing insight into the process&amp;rsquo;s memory space, file descriptor list, symbolic links to files on disk, and other system information. &lt;code&gt;lsof&lt;/code&gt; uses this and other kernel internal state information to generate its output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the information above, you can retrieve the data by examining &lt;code&gt;/proc/&amp;lt;PID&amp;gt;/fd/&amp;lt;descriptor&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, to recover &lt;code&gt;/var/log/secure&lt;/code&gt;, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Check &lt;code&gt;/var/log/secure&lt;/code&gt;, confirming its absence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/6c18c569526d125bae3f25506cd5ec33.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085921&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Use &lt;code&gt;lsof&lt;/code&gt; to check if any process is currently accessing &lt;code&gt;/var/log/secure&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/8461eb12150d46a0207768619be58e61.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085930&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. From the information above, PID 1264 (rsyslogd) has opened the file with a file descriptor of 4. It&amp;rsquo;s marked as deleted. Therefore, you can check the corresponding information in &lt;code&gt;/proc/1264/fd/4&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/4f325beddb0b3eda8e6ba836f8ec3ad7.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085938&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. You can recover the data by redirecting it to a file using I/O redirection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/5c36a1b092df4eacf143d1171a19d651.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510085950&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. Confirm the existence of &lt;code&gt;/var/log/secure&lt;/code&gt; again. This method is particularly useful for many applications, especially log files and databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/46b775fce5dcc17d6114c49eb060460b.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240510090000&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above is the method I summarized for dealing with Linux intrusion. It can generally handle most problems. If you encounter an unresolved issue, it is best to seek advice from a professional IT operations and maintenance engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may not have written it completely correctly, so if you have different opinions, please leave a comment and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
