<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Read on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/tags/read/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Read on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2023 huizhou92</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 20:49:29 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://huizhou92.com/tags/read/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Information Channels  I Use -2024</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/information-channels-i-use-2024/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 20:49:29 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/information-channels-i-use-2024/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;channels&#34;&gt;Channels
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let me get straight to the point and share the channels I rely on to gather information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newsletters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-9000447749076746&#34;
crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;ins class=&#34;adsbygoogle&#34;
    style=&#34;display:block; text-align:center;&#34;
    data-ad-layout=&#34;in-article&#34;
    data-ad-format=&#34;fluid&#34;
    data-ad-client=&#34;ca-pub-9000447749076746&#34;
    data-ad-slot=&#34;5063552270&#34;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was first published in the Medium MPP plan. If you are a Medium user, please follow me on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.huizhou92.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;RSS is my go-to channel for information. I use Reeder 5 to subscribe to RSS feeds locally. As soon as I arrive at the office, the first thing I do is open the software and browse through the newly added articles. If I come across any useful ones, I tag them and save them for later when I have some free time. I try to keep the number of unread articles to a minimum, as an overwhelming backlog might lead to a loss of interest in using Reeder 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in 2023, I began exploring newsletters as a way to stay informed. Initially, I was hesitant to clutter my email inbox (I only have a personal and a work email) with various newsletters. However, I stumbled upon &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omnivore.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;omnivore&lt;/a&gt;, an absolute gem of an application. It allows me to subscribe to articles and emails, import books, and make annotations. I can even export these annotations to Obsidian, which perfectly aligns with my workflow. At times, I find myself storing and annotating content from RSS feeds in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omnivore.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;omnivore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsletters come in two types. The first type is the weekly kind, where others curate and provide brief comments. I often discover interesting articles in these newsletters and add them to my RSS list. Reading them feels light and enjoyable. The second type consists of meticulously crafted articles by authors, offering in-depth and rich content. Reading such articles requires setting aside dedicated time as they can be quite extensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both email and RSS are considered &amp;ldquo;ancient&amp;rdquo; internet protocols. However, the longer I use them (or perhaps as I grow older), the more I appreciate their stability, longevity, and the rich ecosystem they provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books and research papers have been a constant in my life since my student days. Every year, I make it a point to read a substantial number of physical books. Newsletters offer a different experience, even compared to e-books. I find it hard to describe the feeling, but I believe that even in this digital age, we should not forget the value of physical books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcasts&#34;&gt;Podcasts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Podcasts have become an integral part of my daily routine, particularly during my commute to work. I have developed a fondness for finance and history podcasts. Auditory information consumption is faster for me than visual information, although podcasts don&amp;rsquo;t offer the same information density as text. Instead, they provide a comforting presence during commutes, workouts, or when engaging in mechanical tasks—a voice that often brings a smile to my face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;videos&#34;&gt;Videos
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;More and more people are recognizing YouTube as the ultimate university. Nowadays, I often turn to YouTube for search queries rather than Google, especially when I&amp;rsquo;m seeking practical knowledge. Finding a video tutorial allows me to quickly grasp concepts without the complexity of reading lengthy instruction manuals. YouTube hosts a vast array of knowledge-based videos, with many creators specializing in their respective fields. For instance, the technology videos I frequently watch are always up to date. Whenever a new technology emerges, particularly in the realm of front-end development, YouTube promptly provides videos for trial, evaluation, troubleshooting, and tutorials. If I wish to learn computer fundamentals, there are content creators who explain them in a comprehensive yet accessible manner. Personally, I find that absorbing knowledge from YouTube is faster than reading books. However, I tend to avoid investment-related videos on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To summarize, the software tools I rely on include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reeder 5: A highly efficient local RSS client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omnivore.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Omnivore&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obsidian: A note-taking software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Podcasts:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that each person can discover their own preferred methods of information acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
