<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Compute on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/categories/compute/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Compute on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2023 huizhou92</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://huizhou92.com/categories/compute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Magical Algorithms Written by Two Old Men, Dominating the World!</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/the-magical-algorithms-written-by-two-old-men-dominating-the-world/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 18:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/the-magical-algorithms-written-by-two-old-men-dominating-the-world/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/f99c3cfdce323ee7f49a9fc7cbf2ffc9.png" alt="Featured image of post The Magical Algorithms Written by Two Old Men, Dominating the World!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an ordinary person, when you browse the web, you may not realize that the web pages sent to you by the server are actually compressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like a programmer, press F12 in the browser, you&amp;rsquo;ll find something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/3dc37c7d0ce9c1a32f87d44adbd5ef8e.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Image&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It means: In order to save bandwidth and provide speed, I (the server) compressed the content using gzip, and you (the browser) need to decompress it to view it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In HTTP compression, besides gzip, there are also algorithms like compress, deflate, br, etc., which can be dazzling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, all these compression algorithms have an ancestor: &lt;strong&gt;LZ algorithm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LZ comes from the names of two people: Abraham &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;empel and Jacob &lt;strong&gt;Z&lt;/strong&gt;iv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/f99c3cfdce323ee7f49a9fc7cbf2ffc9.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Image&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of them passed away in 2023, living a long life, with Lempel living to be 86 years old and Ziv living to be 91 years old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;origin&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Origin&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data compression can be divided into two types: lossy compression, such as MP3, JPEG, where some unimportant data is deleted during compression, and lossless compression, where binary bits magically disappear, making files significantly smaller, facilitating storage and transmission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1948, after Claude Shannon founded information theory, everyone has been working on one thing: how to find the optimal coding to compress a piece of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shannon and Fano were the first to propose the &lt;strong&gt;Shannon-Fano coding&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/d34b40c3bd6dba146e405c6328ffe57a.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425184027&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It constructs a binary tree from top to bottom by grouping symbols.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/5fa4f771858988a54a24f909877cec3a.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425183959&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this method is not the optimal solution and the encoding is not a prefix code, making it prone to ambiguity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, while teaching information theory at MIT, Fano challenged his students: either take the final exam or improve existing data compression algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A graduate student named Huffman didn&amp;rsquo;t like exams, so he chose the latter path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huffman didn&amp;rsquo;t know that even the famous Shannon struggled with this problem. He researched for several months, developed various methods, but none worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as he was about to give up and throw his notes into the trash, a wonderful and elegant algorithm crossed his mind: build a binary tree from bottom to top based on the frequency of characters, which is the famous Huffman algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huffman&amp;rsquo;s algorithm is called &amp;ldquo;optimal coding&amp;rdquo; and achieves two goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) No character encoding is a prefix of another character encoding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) The total length of the information encoding is minimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Huffman algorithm is excellent, it has a huge limitation: &lt;strong&gt;it requires obtaining the probability of each character appearing first&lt;/strong&gt;, and then compression encoding can be done, which is often impossible in many cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1970s, with the emergence of the Internet, this problem became more prominent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to compress data while reading it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;breakthrough&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breakthrough&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ziv and Lempel from the Technion-Israel Institute of Technology jointly challenged this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two were a good team, with Ziv being good at statistics and information theory, while Lempel excelled in Boolean algebra and computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/1324380a2e44a3dac2eba5ee62ab490e.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425184054&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1977, they both came to Bell Labs for academic sabbaticals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic sabbatical, also known as &amp;ldquo;intellectual leave,&amp;rdquo; gives you a long period of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;leave (like six months) after working for a few years, during which you can do whatever you want, and it&amp;rsquo;s paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sabbaticals of the big shots are interesting. For example, Ken Thompson, the inventor of Unix, returned to his alma mater, Berkeley, during his sabbatical and spread Unix there, inspiring Bill Joy and others to develop BSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ziv and Lempel were similar. They went to Bell Labs in the United States for academic sabbaticals and co-authored a paper during their &amp;ldquo;sabbatical&amp;rdquo;: &amp;ldquo;A Universal Algorithm for Sequential Data Compression,&amp;rdquo; proposing an algorithm based on a &amp;ldquo;sliding window,&amp;rdquo; which does not directly consider character frequencies but instead finds repeated data blocks (such as strings, byte sequences, etc.) and references the positions where these data blocks appeared previously.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/6e5efd3753463265af8a4e84c007e4ca.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425184125&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This algorithm is LZ77, which is applicable to any type of data, requires no preprocessing (statistical character appearance probabilities), and achieves extremely high compression ratios with just one pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following year, they continued their efforts and improved LZ77 to become LZ78, which could perfectly reconstruct data from compressed data and was more efficient than previous algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;chaos&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chaos&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;An invaluable treasure like the LZ algorithm remained in the theoretical realm for several years without widespread use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until 1984, when Terry Welch of DEC created the &lt;strong&gt;LZW algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; based on LZ, which was used in Unix&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;compress&lt;/strong&gt; program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the widespread dissemination of Unix, the LZ algorithm began to enter the fast lane of rapid development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it also entered an era of chaotic competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1985, Thom Henderson, while downloading files from BBS, found it tedious to download one by one, as dial-up internet was too slow. So he wrote a software called &lt;strong&gt;ARC&lt;/strong&gt;, which could compress multiple files into one, making it much more convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1986, Phillip Katz discovered ARC, liked it, but felt that the compression speed was too slow. So he rolled up his sleeves, rewrote the key compression and decompression parts in assembly language, and created &lt;strong&gt;PKARC&lt;/strong&gt;, which he started selling.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/da855761fb63597eb7de689e7a5db345.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425184142&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/5dea706890fb605ba66eebaae69a27ad.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425184148&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
When Thom Henderson saw his business being snatched away, he sued Phillip Katz, and the reasons were sufficient: the comments and spelling errors in your PKARC are the same as my ARC, you&amp;rsquo;re plagiarizing! Also, while my ARC is open source, the protocol specifies that you can only view it, not modify it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, ARC won the lawsuit, and Phillip Katz paid tens of thousands of dollars in damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genius Phillip Katz was naturally not satisfied. He studied the LZ77 algorithm and the Huffman algorithm, combined them, and created a new compression algorithm (&lt;strong&gt;deflate&lt;/strong&gt;) and a new file format (&lt;strong&gt;zip&lt;/strong&gt;), as well as the new software &lt;strong&gt;PKZIP&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/9f2582c7f818ccae3a8c3944585fda8a.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425184157&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
PKZIP quickly outperformed ARC in both compression ratio and decompression speed, and quickly dominated the DOS era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the ZIP format was open, the open-source info-zip group also released the open-source, free &lt;strong&gt;unzip&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;zip&lt;/strong&gt;, implementing the deflate algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, Jean-loup Gailly and Mark Adler developed the famous &lt;strong&gt;gzip&lt;/strong&gt; (file format + utility) based on deflate, replacing compress on Unix.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/de55eace3bd613ed7147e1313877cc8b.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425184253&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gzip is the HTTP compression format seen at the beginning of the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1991, Nico Mak felt dissatisfied with the command line of PKZIP, so he developed a front-end for Windows 3.1 based on PKZIP (later replaced by the open-source info-zip), allowing people to compress files using a graphical interface. This is the famous WinZip.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/05c9824cdc3df564ea258ac5afdc3994.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425184442&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2024/04/155a024cec52f0c9b8e2c5bd10400acf.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240425184447&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Despite WinZip&amp;rsquo;s success, it was still &amp;ldquo;parasitic&amp;rdquo; on the Windows platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users find that WinZip has an exquisite interface and is user-friendly. There is no need to remember those annoying parameters and compression can be completed with a few clicks of the mouse.&lt;br&gt;
WinZip quickly took over all PCs and became one of the most popular shareware programs in the 1990s.&lt;br&gt;
Windows intervened and simply integrated Zip functionality into the operating system, ending everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;From LZ77 to LZW, compress, Deflate, gzip&amp;hellip; Lossless compression algorithms have been continuously patched and gradually formed into a huge family. However, no matter how they change, their principles and ideas are not much different from the original LZ algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These algorithms help us compress images, compress text, compress content transmitted over the Internet, and have become an indispensable part of our daily lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no exaggeration to say that the LZ algorithm and its descendants have dominated the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Aws ec2 switch to ipv6,Save $43 per year</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/aws-ec2-switch-to-ipv6save-43-per-year/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 20:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/aws-ec2-switch-to-ipv6save-43-per-year/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*32WLSHGCAPKEBvI3" alt="Featured image of post Aws ec2 switch to ipv6,Save $43 per year" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;IPv6 has been around for a long time, and I have dealt with many IPv6 tasks in my work. However, I never thought about switching my EC2 instance to IPv4. Yesterday, while going through my email trash, I came across a message stating that AWS will start charging for IPv4 addresses from February 1, 2024. This caught my attention, so I decided to switch my EC2 instance to IPv6 today. The process was a bit of a hassle. This article is not only applicable to EC2 instances but should also work for other Linux hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*SHE5MfrCO4t2ckNL.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is first published in the medium MPP plan. If you are a medium user, please follow me in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.hxzhouh.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;adding-an-ipv6-address-toec2&#34;&gt;Adding an IPv6 Address to EC2
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since my EC2 instance’s DNS resolution is handled by Cloudflare, I mainly referred to this blog post: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.cloudflare.com/zh-cn/amazon-2bn-ipv4-tax-how-avoid-paying-zh-cn/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Amazon’s $2bn IPv4 Tax — and How to Avoid Paying It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also, the official AWS documentation on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/zh_cn/vpc/latest/userguide/vpc-migrate-ipv6.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Migrating Your VPC from IPv4 to IPv6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that the demo in the “Migrating Your VPC from IPv4 to IPv6” documentation assumes that the VPC has both a public and a private subnet. If you, like me, only have a public subnet, you can skip that part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*ESBOHJRAC3rtmcsk.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say, AWS documentation is well-written, and there’s a lot to learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result after completing the setup should look like this, with both IPv4 and IPv6 addresses. Make sure to add the same rules for IPv6 in the security group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*N95oY6RVuVkurxfn.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;application-support&#34;&gt;Application Support
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my EC2 instance, I only have Nginx and Docker running, and I usually log in via SSH. So, I need to add IPv6 support for Nginx and SSH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;nginx&#34;&gt;Nginx
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;For your HTTP server block (the one listening on port 80), add the line &lt;code&gt;listen [::]:80;&lt;/code&gt;. This allows Nginx to listen to both IPv4 and IPv6 HTTP traffic. Your modified server block should look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;server &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;     listen 80&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;     listen &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;::&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;:80&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;     server_name hexo.hxzhouh.com&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;     &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;301&lt;/span&gt; https://&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$host$request_uri&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For each HTTPS server block (those listening on port 443), add &lt;code&gt;listen [::]:443 ssl;&lt;/code&gt; inside each block. This enables Nginx to listen for HTTPS traffic on IPv6. For example, for the first HTTPS server block, you need to make the following modification:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;server &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;     listen &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;443&lt;/span&gt; ssl&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;     listen &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;::&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;:443 ssl&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;     server_name hexo.hxzhouh.com&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;     &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# other configurations...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make these modifications for each HTTPS server block. Then, test the Nginx configuration with &lt;code&gt;Nginx -t&lt;/code&gt;. If there are no issues, reload the Nginx configuration with &lt;code&gt;systemctl reload nginx&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sshd&#34;&gt;SSHD
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;code&gt;sshd_config&lt;/code&gt; file, uncomment the line &lt;code&gt;AddressFamily any&lt;/code&gt; (i.e., remove the preceding &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;) to enable IPv6 listening for SSH and other applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;vim /etc/ssh/sshd_config
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt; ​
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#Port 22&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt; AddressFamily any
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt; AddressFamily inet
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#ListenAddress 0.0.0.0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#ListenAddress ::&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, restart SSHD with &lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl reload sshd&lt;/code&gt;. Use the &lt;code&gt;netstat -tupln&lt;/code&gt; command to check if SSH is successfully listening on IPv6. If you see the following output, it means SSH is listening on IPv6:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*x564Ur3tmy5qQIOt.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the application layer modifications are complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dns-configuration&#34;&gt;DNS Configuration
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, in Cloudflare, modify the DNS settings by changing the previous IPv4 A records to AAAA records for IPv6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*Qpu-dV3-6obShvN4.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;test&#34;&gt;Test
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Test everything to make sure it’s working fine, and then you can delete the IPv4 address to avoid being charged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uppublished: Running instances cannot have their IPv4 addresses removed, but you can rebuild them using an AMI. It’s a bit of a hassle, but at least AWS won’t send me any more emails. ✌️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://repost.aws/questions/QUVmpO9BWGSuGwQh5tXk3f5w/how-to-remove-ipv4-public-ip-address-from-ec2-instances-before-february-2024-ipv6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How to remove IPv4 public IP address from EC2 instances before February 2024? (IPv6)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
