<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>talk on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/categories/talk/</link>
        <description>Recent content in talk on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2023 huizhou92</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 21:17:49 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://huizhou92.com/categories/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Future of Endpoint Management</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/the-future-of-endpoint-management/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 21:17:49 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/the-future-of-endpoint-management/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our post-analysis has uncovered a critical issue: credential leakage is the most prevalent cause of hacker attacks. Hackers exploit these credentials to gain a foothold on users&amp;rsquo; endpoint devices, such as desktops, laptops, or mobile devices. These endpoint devices, serving as the primary gateway to enterprise networks, are frequently targeted by attackers for illicit purposes. Alarmingly, a Ponemon survey found that &lt;strong&gt;68%&lt;/strong&gt; of organizations have experienced at least one successful endpoint attack in the past year, underscoring the urgent need for enhanced endpoint security measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-9000447749076746&#34;
crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;ins class=&#34;adsbygoogle&#34;
    style=&#34;display:block; text-align:center;&#34;
    data-ad-layout=&#34;in-article&#34;
    data-ad-format=&#34;fluid&#34;
    data-ad-client=&#34;ca-pub-9000447749076746&#34;
    data-ad-slot=&#34;5063552270&#34;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was first published in the Medium MPP plan. If you are a Medium user, please follow me on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.huizhou92.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, IT teams heavily rely on specialized software for endpoint protection. However, endpoint devices, both online and offline, have become the preferred tools for almost all employees in their work. Therefore, endpoint management is a fundamental component of IT teams&amp;rsquo; enterprise infrastructure strategy. However, the rapid shift to online work methods, regardless of geographical location, has posed urgent and significant challenges for organizations still relying on more traditional approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When establishing cross-endpoint visibility and security controls, both IT and security teams need to understand that each endpoint should bear some, if not full, responsibility for its own security. Unlike traditional network security approaches, the security measures implemented in this case apply to the entire network rather than just individual devices or servers. Therefore, ensuring resilience in all endpoints is crucial for successfully implementing defense strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-state-of-endpoint-management&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The State of Endpoint Management&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organizations should establish a simple form of endpoint management and security management system, such as unified endpoint management, antivirus software, or anti-malware programs, at least across their device clusters. Many organizations go beyond these basic measures and utilize endpoint security encryption technologies, intrusion detection, and behavior-blocking elements to identify and prevent threats or risky behaviors from endpoint users or intruders. However, as the total number of devices in enterprises and the average number of applications installed on these systems rapidly increase, IT and security teams face increasingly complex tasks. Consequently, managers often find that endpoint management consumes excessive time and hinders their focus on other strategic priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, users expect to have a good and consistent endpoint experience regardless of their location. Their main concern is that their technology works effectively if they have continuous access to the reliable resources they need. This means that when users work remotely, IT teams need higher levels of visibility to ensure consistent experiences across different locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;driving-trends-for-the-future-of-endpoint-management&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Driving Trends for the Future of Endpoint Management&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To address these challenges, experts in the industry predict that future cross-endpoint management tools will undergo further simplification and modernization. Three distinct trends explain the specific requirements from the new era of remote work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration of local endpoint security&lt;/strong&gt;: More organizations now understand that endpoint security and access security go hand in hand, and establishing resilient zero-trust principles from endpoints to network boundaries is crucial for modern security posture. 51% of organizations have encountered attackers accessing company data by targeting endpoints. Therefore, software-defined boundaries or zero-trust network access (ZTNA) methods no longer rely on contextual factors such as time or geography when granting user access. They also consider device configurations and the security posture of the devices. In the future, most IT and security practitioners will desire a unified endpoint and secure access platform to consolidate visibility and control for addressing risks in cross-endpoint access, applications, and networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resilient, self-healing, and trusted systems&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensuring resilience in every endpoint is crucial for successfully implementing defense strategies. Self-healing cybersecurity systems enhance security and IT productivity while simplifying the management and protection of today&amp;rsquo;s highly distributed infrastructure. Malicious actors often exploit human errors to disable existing security measures on enterprise devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-healing solutions can monitor critical applications to counter these threats to prevent tampering or degradation. Automation can be used to repair or reinstall problematic or lost applications. However, different self-healing cybersecurity systems are established in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-healing can exist at three levels: application, operating system, and firmware. According to Forrester Research, firmware-based tools embedded within devices are the most important, as they ensure the proper functioning of everything on the device (e.g., endpoint agents, VPNs, and various software). This technology remains intact even if administrators reconfigure the endpoint or replace the hard drive. In the future, organizations should prioritize vendors that offer persistent and self-healing capabilities when making final purchasing decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on consistent user endpoint experience&lt;/strong&gt;: In addition to IT manageability and core security aspects, organizations must focus on the remote workers themselves, ensuring they have insights and visibility from endpoints to network edges that impact the end-user experience. This includes addressing device issues (e.g., outdated OS systems, disk drive capacity), home office Wi-Fi and network issues, VPN tunnel performance issues, and application-related problems while enabling IT to quickly identify and rectify the root causes. On the other hand, many organizations have shifted to using Digital Experience Monitoring (DEM) tools to help identify technical performance issues and adjust application performance to achieve business objectives. In the future, leading endpoint management tools will incorporate the collection of endpoint user experience telemetry and analysis into their products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, the modernization process of endpoint management strategies is progressing smoothly. Combining the aforementioned trends will provide employees with a better digital experience and help organizations improve operational efficiency while reducing the attack surface.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Information Channels  I Use -2024</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/information-channels-i-use-2024/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 20:49:29 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/information-channels-i-use-2024/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;channels&#34;&gt;Channels
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let me get straight to the point and share the channels I rely on to gather information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newsletters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-9000447749076746&#34;
crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;ins class=&#34;adsbygoogle&#34;
    style=&#34;display:block; text-align:center;&#34;
    data-ad-layout=&#34;in-article&#34;
    data-ad-format=&#34;fluid&#34;
    data-ad-client=&#34;ca-pub-9000447749076746&#34;
    data-ad-slot=&#34;5063552270&#34;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was first published in the Medium MPP plan. If you are a Medium user, please follow me on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.huizhou92.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;RSS is my go-to channel for information. I use Reeder 5 to subscribe to RSS feeds locally. As soon as I arrive at the office, the first thing I do is open the software and browse through the newly added articles. If I come across any useful ones, I tag them and save them for later when I have some free time. I try to keep the number of unread articles to a minimum, as an overwhelming backlog might lead to a loss of interest in using Reeder 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in 2023, I began exploring newsletters as a way to stay informed. Initially, I was hesitant to clutter my email inbox (I only have a personal and a work email) with various newsletters. However, I stumbled upon &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omnivore.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;omnivore&lt;/a&gt;, an absolute gem of an application. It allows me to subscribe to articles and emails, import books, and make annotations. I can even export these annotations to Obsidian, which perfectly aligns with my workflow. At times, I find myself storing and annotating content from RSS feeds in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omnivore.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;omnivore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsletters come in two types. The first type is the weekly kind, where others curate and provide brief comments. I often discover interesting articles in these newsletters and add them to my RSS list. Reading them feels light and enjoyable. The second type consists of meticulously crafted articles by authors, offering in-depth and rich content. Reading such articles requires setting aside dedicated time as they can be quite extensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both email and RSS are considered &amp;ldquo;ancient&amp;rdquo; internet protocols. However, the longer I use them (or perhaps as I grow older), the more I appreciate their stability, longevity, and the rich ecosystem they provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books and research papers have been a constant in my life since my student days. Every year, I make it a point to read a substantial number of physical books. Newsletters offer a different experience, even compared to e-books. I find it hard to describe the feeling, but I believe that even in this digital age, we should not forget the value of physical books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcasts&#34;&gt;Podcasts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Podcasts have become an integral part of my daily routine, particularly during my commute to work. I have developed a fondness for finance and history podcasts. Auditory information consumption is faster for me than visual information, although podcasts don&amp;rsquo;t offer the same information density as text. Instead, they provide a comforting presence during commutes, workouts, or when engaging in mechanical tasks—a voice that often brings a smile to my face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;videos&#34;&gt;Videos
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;More and more people are recognizing YouTube as the ultimate university. Nowadays, I often turn to YouTube for search queries rather than Google, especially when I&amp;rsquo;m seeking practical knowledge. Finding a video tutorial allows me to quickly grasp concepts without the complexity of reading lengthy instruction manuals. YouTube hosts a vast array of knowledge-based videos, with many creators specializing in their respective fields. For instance, the technology videos I frequently watch are always up to date. Whenever a new technology emerges, particularly in the realm of front-end development, YouTube promptly provides videos for trial, evaluation, troubleshooting, and tutorials. If I wish to learn computer fundamentals, there are content creators who explain them in a comprehensive yet accessible manner. Personally, I find that absorbing knowledge from YouTube is faster than reading books. However, I tend to avoid investment-related videos on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To summarize, the software tools I rely on include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reeder 5: A highly efficient local RSS client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omnivore.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Omnivore&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obsidian: A note-taking software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple Podcasts:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that each person can discover their own preferred methods of information acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Innovation and Tradition: Using Images Instead of Video Streams for Live Feeds</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/innovation-and-tradition-using-images-instead-of-video-streams-for-live-feeds/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 09:54:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/innovation-and-tradition-using-images-instead-of-video-streams-for-live-feeds/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I stumbled upon an intriguing &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://linearcam.city.fuefuki.yamanashi.jp/index.html?p=2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;website&lt;/a&gt; showcasing numerous web cameras operated by the Japanese government. Surprisingly, these cameras offer live feeds by refreshing a single image every 0.1 seconds. Initially, I thought this was a sign of governmental inefficiency or outdated IT infrastructure in Japan. However, upon further reflection, I realized that the underlying reasons may not be so simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-9000447749076746&#34;
crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;ins class=&#34;adsbygoogle&#34;
    style=&#34;display:block; text-align:center;&#34;
    data-ad-layout=&#34;in-article&#34;
    data-ad-format=&#34;fluid&#34;
    data-ad-client=&#34;ca-pub-9000447749076746&#34;
    data-ad-slot=&#34;5063552270&#34;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
(adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is first published in the medium MPP plan. If you are a medium user, please follow me in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.huizhou92.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Europe and the United States have long-standing systems, some of which have been running for decades. Similarly, these Japanese government web cameras were set up over 20 years ago, during a time when 56k dial-up and ADSL were the standard. Given the limited bandwidth of that era, using a 0.1-second image refresh to create a live feed was quite practical. The fact that this system has operated smoothly for over two decades speaks volumes about its stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;technological-progress-and-practical-compatibility&#34;&gt;Technological Progress and Practical Compatibility
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the span of just 30 years, we’ve witnessed massive transformations from the personal computer era to the mobile internet age. Consider the 1994 release of the original “The Need for Speed”:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/06/04a2aae2338b42431292f66133d19705.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Pasted image 20240622172148&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now compare it to the latest “&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3UDpL-gb-FI&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Need For Speed: Unbound&lt;/a&gt;,” which features near-photorealistic graphics. This is a testament to the triumph of technological advancement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a tech professional, I initially assumed that government public service webcams should at least offer 1080p high-bitrate video or even VR capabilities. But is this really necessary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-human-touch-in-tech-choices&#34;&gt;The Human Touch in Tech Choices
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only a small fraction of the global population uses the latest smartphones. Even if Apple sells 100 million iPhones a year, the total number in use might be around 500 million. At least 60% of people use devices that can’t handle high-definition video due to display and network limitations. The Japanese government’s seemingly clunky method of refreshing images every 0.1 seconds actually boasts the broadest compatibility, supporting devices from Windows 98 to the latest MacBook Pro. This approach ensures the widest reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-value-and-longevity-of-older-devices&#34;&gt;The Value and Longevity of Older Devices
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past 30 years, we’ve accumulated many infrastructure and personal devices. This is a valuable asset. While new devices are more advanced, considering the compatibility of older devices when developing new products can extend their lifespan and avoid unnecessary waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-practical-benefits-of-low-tech-solutions&#34;&gt;The Practical Benefits of Low-Tech Solutions
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider a train station in Niigata, Japan, which displays its departure times via a web camera focused on the station&amp;rsquo;s schedule board. This approach might seem “low-tech,” but it has numerous practical advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Cost&lt;/strong&gt;: No need for complex systems or apps; maintenance is simple and cost-effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wide Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt;: Even basic 2G internet and older phones can display the schedule, ensuring information is widely accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advanced-isnt-always-better&#34;&gt;Advanced Isn’t Always Better
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When choosing technology for projects, practical considerations often outweigh pursuing the latest advancements. In many cases, the most successful projects are those that use the minimum viable product (MVP) approach to meet essential needs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Needs&lt;/strong&gt;: Understand the target user’s requirements and device capabilities to select the most appropriate technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost-Effectiveness&lt;/strong&gt;: Evaluate the cost-benefit ratio and choose the most economically sensible technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;/strong&gt;: Consider the long-term sustainability and maintenance costs to ensure stable, ongoing operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While technological advancements offer exciting possibilities, selecting the most suitable—not necessarily the most advanced—technology often yields the best results. This approach best uses existing resources and demonstrates a commitment to practicality and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Crafting Your Second Brain Lessons Learned from My Note-Taking Journey</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/crafting-your-second-brain-lessons-learned-from-my-note-taking-journey/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 23:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/crafting-your-second-brain-lessons-learned-from-my-note-taking-journey/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://images.yixiao9206.cn/blog-images/2024/05/5ab6b54893dc2241704444526269572a.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Crafting Your Second Brain Lessons Learned from My Note-Taking Journey" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the past few years building my second brain, and here are some lessons I’ve learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequent-switching-of-note-taking-softwareblogging-systems&#34;&gt;Frequent Switching of Note-Taking Software/Blogging Systems
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried EverNote, WizNote, VNote, CSDN blog, Google blogspot, WordPress, only to end up scattering my blogs across multiple corners of the internet. The solution? Going all in one. I’ve now settled on Obsidian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;constantly-switching-noteformats&#34;&gt;Constantly Switching Note Formats
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve experimented with txt, orgmode, markdown, rich text, and more, only to find myself frustrated with format conversions. Similar to the first point, each note system may not be universally compatible. The reason I chose Obsidian is for its markdown syntax. If need be, I can easily migrate it to any note system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mixing-fleeting-thoughts-with-truly-usefulnotes&#34;&gt;Mixing Fleeting Thoughts with Truly Useful Notes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fleeting thoughts serve to capture a moment of inspiration, but it’s only meaningful if you revisit them within a day or two and turn them into useful, relevant notes. Without timely review, good ideas drown in a sea of whims. Most of our daily thoughts are insignificant and should be discarded, while those with potential significance must be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mixing-project-notes-with-knowledge-notes&#34;&gt;Mixing Project Notes with Knowledge Notes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only recording notes relevant to specific projects leads to the loss of interesting insights or ideas during the project. The correct approach is to extract universal knowledge from projects. I recommend using the P.A.R.A method to organize notes. For more information on P.A.R.A, you can refer to this &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fortelabs.com/blog/para/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;obsessive-note-organization&#34;&gt;Obsessive Note Organization
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A large pile of notes leads to an urge to organize knowledge, but too many attempts can affect the confidence to keep recording. The solution is to define the areas of interest and responsibility and not completely adopt a bottom-up knowledge management approach. When reaching the point of psychological pressure, use the MOCS (Maps of Content) method to organize notes (bidirectional linking is definitely worth trying). The most important aspect of a knowledge management system is to record your insights in one place, with the same format, and consistent standards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
