<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Hacker_news on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/tags/hacker_news/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Hacker_news on huizhou92&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Copyright © 2023 huizhou92</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:21:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://huizhou92.com/tags/hacker_news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Playing Snake in Your Browser’s Address Bar: When the Internet Was Still Fun</title>
        <link>https://huizhou92.com/p/playing-snake-in-your-browsers-address-bar-when-the-internet-was-still-fun/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:21:30 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://huizhou92.com/p/playing-snake-in-your-browsers-address-bar-when-the-internet-was-still-fun/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2025/10/c61a3f89ebd38ec64ecc25f6232db78b.png" alt="Featured image of post Playing Snake in Your Browser’s Address Bar: When the Internet Was Still Fun" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open Chrome, type &lt;code&gt;https://demian.ferrei.ro/snake#&lt;/code&gt; into the address bar, and you’ll suddenly see a string of strange characters.&lt;br&gt;
Yes, you read that right. Keep your eyes on the address bar and control the direction with the arrow keys or WASD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll see a little snake made of odd-looking symbols (░░░░░░░⠠⠤⠄⡀░░) crawling around inside the address bar, eating food, and growing longer. The entire game plays out inside that thin text field you usually only use to type URLs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images.hxzhouh.com/blog-images/2025/10/5ea3b9a9457de17c348e4a8631605888.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Area&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s right — this is a fully functional Snake game running entirely inside the browser’s URL bar.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, this decade-old project suddenly blew up on Hacker News, racking up 840 upvotes and hundreds of comments. The first reaction from many people was: &lt;em&gt;“This is insane. How did you even come up with this?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the story behind this game is even crazier — and it reveals something important about what the modern internet has lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-random-curiosity-sparks-a-technical-adventure&#34;&gt;A Random Curiosity Sparks a Technical Adventure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The creator, Francisco Uzo, recalls the project’s origins: &lt;em&gt;“I just wanted to understand how the Braille system worked.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the essence of hacker culture — &lt;strong&gt;not solving a problem, but chasing pure curiosity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he dug into Braille, he noticed something fascinating: each Braille symbol is a 2x4 dot matrix, eight positions in total, each either “raised” or “flat.” That gives 2^8 = 256 possible combinations. And Unicode happens to support all 256 Braille characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One night around 3 a.m., it hit him: &lt;strong&gt;“Wait, this is basically an 8-bit pixel character set!”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That spark — when two unrelated ideas suddenly connect — is exactly the kind of joy hackers live for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then came the classic hacker instinct: &lt;strong&gt;don’t ask whether it’s useful — just build it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implementation was full of clever hacks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping the game world onto Braille character grids, each character acting as a 2x4 pixel block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using solid dots (⣿) for the snake’s body and blank Braille (⠀) for empty space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leveraging JavaScript’s &lt;code&gt;history.replaceState()&lt;/code&gt; API to update the URL in real time without polluting the history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refreshing the entire frame each tick so the game animates smoothly inside the address bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francisco’s openness was just as “hacker-ish”: &lt;em&gt;“The source code isn’t minified or obfuscated. Just hit Ctrl+U and you’ll see everything.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing was only a few hundred lines of JavaScript — concise, readable, and elegant. &lt;strong&gt;In the hacker mindset, code isn’t just for execution — it should also be legible, learnable, and inspiring.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wait-why-does-my-game-look-broken&#34;&gt;Wait… Why Does My Game Look Broken?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you try the game today, you might just see a mess of &lt;code&gt;%20&lt;/code&gt;, backslashes, and gibberish. The snake barely moves — or sometimes the game doesn’t run at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s not your fault. It’s not even the code’s fault. The browser has changed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francisco admitted, &lt;em&gt;“This project was written for browsers ten years ago. Since then, browsers have made certain ‘security improvements’ that severely limit what’s possible in the URL bar.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most critical change? &lt;strong&gt;Modern browsers now forcefully escape all spaces in URLs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the game’s design, the blank Braille character (⠀) represented empty space. However, browsers now escape those characters as &lt;code&gt;%20&lt;/code&gt; or something else, which ruins the visual output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francisco even built a fallback system that measured text widths via Canvas and replaced escaped characters on the fly — but it only worked partially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He appealed to browser bug trackers. Developers sympathized but ultimately concluded: &lt;strong&gt;“As always, security outweighs fun.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, users’ experiences varied wildly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some people on Chrome scored over 2,000 points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others saw a screen full of garbage in Firefox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On iOS Safari, the game sometimes didn’t even render&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some users found their browsing history polluted with every single game frame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same code, drastically different behavior across browsers. That’s just the reality of modern web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-golden-age-of-weird-browser-games&#34;&gt;The Golden Age of “Weird Browser Games”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Snake in the address bar wasn’t the only project of its kind. The Hacker News discussion turned into a nostalgia trip, with people recalling a whole wave of unconventional browser experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2048-in-the-url&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2048 In the URL&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone linked to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aquova.net/games/2048/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://aquova.net/games/2048/&lt;/a&gt; — a port of the once-famous puzzle game, implemented entirely inside the address bar using the same Braille and URL-refresh trick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;snake-in-the-browser-tab-title&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snake In the Browser Tab Title&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Francisco mentioned that someone on Reddit made a version that runs inside the tab’s title instead. It was basically a compromise — no longer in the address bar, but safe from URL escaping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tinyjs-snake&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TinyJS Snake&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2023, another developer built &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://danielgjackson.github.io/tinyjs#snake&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a similar Snake clone&lt;/a&gt; using a different technique. At the time, browser restrictions weren’t as strict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3d-worlds-in-the-url&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3D Worlds in the URL&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another project took things further: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://matthew.rayfield.world/articles/games-and-graphics-in-popup-url-bars/#:~:text=The%203D%20Room&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an interactive 3D environment rendered through unconventional browser features&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
One commenter joked: &lt;em&gt;“It’s not Doom, but you can walk around in 3D.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do all these have in common? &lt;strong&gt;They were built for fun, out of curiosity, with no concern for practicality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No commercial value. No business use case. Not even “best practices.”&lt;br&gt;
But they embodied the spirit of the early web: &lt;strong&gt;a playground where people could experiment, push boundaries, and have fun.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-are-projects-like-this-so-hard-now&#34;&gt;Why Are Projects Like This So Hard Now?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not just the space escaping problem. Over the past decade, browsers have introduced countless so-called &lt;strong&gt;security improvements&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history-api-limits&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History API Limits&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Francisco originally used &lt;code&gt;history.replaceState()&lt;/code&gt; to update the URL without spamming history entries. Modern browsers now throttle calls to this API, forcing fallback to &lt;code&gt;location.hash&lt;/code&gt; — which clutters your browsing history with every frame of gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;url-length-restrictions&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL Length Restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Different browsers cap URL length anywhere from 2,000 to tens of thousands of characters. Encoding game state into URLs quickly hits those ceilings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;character-set-restrictions&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Character Set Restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;More and more Unicode characters are marked as “unsafe” for URLs. Browsers escape or block them, killing Unicode art projects outright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mobile-compatibility&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Compatibility&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many mobile browsers hide the URL bar entirely while scrolling — making address-bar games literally unplayable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francisco summed it up: &lt;em&gt;“Every browser change since then has made projects like this harder. I got some sympathy in bug trackers, but security always wins.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-security-kills-the-fun&#34;&gt;When Security Kills the Fun
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the fundamental tension:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nobody disputes the importance of browser security.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
URL injection attacks, XSS vulnerabilities, phishing — these are real threats affecting billions of users. Browser developers have a duty to protect people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But every “security improvement” quietly closes off a door to creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Francisco’s code worked flawlessly a decade ago. Today, it’s broken not because it was bad, but because the browser “evolved.” That evolution made the web safer — but also more controlled, more uniform, and frankly… more boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;its-not-just-about-games&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s Not Just About Games&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One Hacker News commenter sneered: &lt;em&gt;“Why don’t people build something useful instead of abusing the internet?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community overwhelmingly pushed back:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The learning value from projects like this is massive.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Creative play matters for skill development too.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This is exactly why I come to HN — 100% hacker spirit.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ChatGPT couldn’t have come up with this. I love the creativity.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best response was simple:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“To most people, this is nothing. To me, it’s insane. How did you even think of this?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s the point.&lt;/strong&gt; The value of projects like this isn’t in utility, but in pure human creativity — driven by curiosity, joy, and the urge to ask &lt;em&gt;“why not?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And every time we “tighten security,” we don’t just close loopholes. We also close off avenues for wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-age-of-ai-human-creativity-matters-more&#34;&gt;In the Age of AI, Human Creativity Matters More
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When asked about AI, Francisco said something striking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This game has been online for ten years. It’s probably in AI training data. A robot might be able to replicate it, but it could never enjoy it. (At least not yet.)”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That gets to the heart of our cultural anxiety today. In an era where ChatGPT can generate code in seconds and Copilot can autocomplete whole functions — what projects are still worth building by hand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer might just lie in this Snake game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can parse Braille characters, understand Unicode, and spit out JavaScript. But AI can’t feel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 3 a.m. epiphany that “Braille could be pixels”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the giddy surprise of watching a snake slither inside a URL bar for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The stubborn joy of debugging escape sequences for hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The quiet pride of seeing strangers enjoy your work a decade later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are &lt;strong&gt;uniquely human creative experiences.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In a world where AI can replicate almost all code, that human spark is more precious than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-need-more-projects-like-this&#34;&gt;We Need More Projects Like This
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Snake in the URL bar went viral, not because it’s useful or profitable, but because it reminded us of something essential:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The internet shouldn’t just be efficient, safe, and standardized. It should also be surprising, playful, and experimental.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Francisco asked himself, “How does Braille work?” ten years ago, he wasn’t solving a business problem or optimizing UX. He was just curious. That curiosity created something that made thousands of strangers smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s increasingly homogeneous, “safe,” and algorithmically optimized internet, we need more of this. Not because it’s useful, but because it reminds us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology isn’t only about efficiency and safety — it should also be about wonder and joy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how many points can &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; score? Does your browser even support it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe the real question is: &lt;strong&gt;what’s the last “useless but fun” project you built?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://huizhou92.com/p/playing-snake-in-your-browsers-address-bar-when-the-internet-was-still-fun/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Long Time Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you find my blog helpful, please subscribe to me via &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://huizhou92.com/index.xml&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or follow me on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://x.com/@piaopiaopig&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.huizhou92.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; account, follow me there. My articles will be published there as soon as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
